sketchbubble.com 2018-06-27

# Privacy Policy

_Effective date: May 25th, 2018_

#### GENERAL INFORMATION

The company **InfoShore Technology Solutions LLP,** with registered office at **IT 2002, IT ZONE, RAMCHANDRAPURA INDUS. AREA, SITAPURA, JAIPUR, Rajasthan (India)** (hereinafter referred to as **"we"** or **"us"** ), in its capacity of data controller regarding the processing of Personal Data, is committed to protecting and respecting the privacy of its users, customers and suppliers, even prospective (hereinafter singularly and collectively referred to as the **"you"** or **"your"** ), pursuant to the applicable national laws on data protection (hereinafter referred to as the **"National Law"** ) and, if you are citizen of a Country in the European Economic Area, also pursuant to the European Regulation no. 679/2016 (hereinafter referred to as the **"GDPR"** ) (hereinafter the National Law and the GDPR will be referred to as the **"Applicable Law"** ).

This policy (hereinafter referred to as the **"Privacy Policy"** ) is aimed to inform you about our practices related to our collection and use of your Personal Data either through our website [www.sketchbubble.com](https://www.sketchbubble.com/) (hereinafter referred to as the "Site") or during the performance of any of our service (hereinafter collectively referred to as the **"Services"** ).

 **"Personal Data"** means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

We invite you to read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our considerations and practices regarding the processing of your Personal Data.

#### SECT. 1 - PERSONAL DATA WE PROCESS

When you visit the Site or when we provide you with our Services, we may collect the following Personal Data:

 **1.1. Information you give us.** You may, through our Site, our Services or other contact channel (e.g., e-mail, etc.), voluntarily provide us Personal Data and/or information and documents containing Personal Data. In particular, such Personal Data may include your name, email, address, order number, financial data, and any other information you send through our customer support. **We will process these data in accordance with the Applicable Law and on the assumption that they refer to you or to third parties who have authorized you to provide them pursuant to an appropriate legal basis which legitimize the processing at stake. In this case, you act as independent data controller, assuming all relevant obligations and responsibilities according to the Applicable Law. In this regard, you hence waive, in the full sense of the term, the right to all disputes, claims, claims for damages due to processing, etc., which may be submitted to us by the said third parties whose Personal Data have been processed through your use of the Site or the Services in breach of the Applicable Law.**

 **1.2. Browsing data.** Computer systems and software procedures used to operate the Site collect some Personal Data, the transmission of which is an integral part of internet communication protocols. This information is not collected to be associated with you but, by its very nature, it may allow you to be identified by processing and associating it with data held by third parties. Among collected Personal Data there are: (i) IP addresses or domain names of the devices used by you to connect to the Site; (ii) the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) of requested resources; (iii) the time of the request, the method used to submit the request to the server; (iv) the size of the file received as a reply; (v) the numeric code indicating the status of the reply given by the server (successful, error, etc.); (vi) other parameters regarding your operating system and device environment.

 **1.3. Cookies and similar technologies.** We may collect Personal Data using cookies. You can find further information on the use of cookie and similar technologies here <https://www.sketchbubble.com/en/cookie-policy>.

#### SECT. 2 - PURPOSES AND LEGAL BASIS OF THE PROCESSING

 **2.1. Purposes.** Personal Data provided by you will be processed by us for the purposes and legal basis specified below :

 **Purposes**|  **Legal basis**  
---|---  
To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information and Services that you requested from us (e.g., create and manage your account, provide our Services, process payments, respond to your inquiries, process the subscription to our newsletter, etc.).| This processing is necessary for the performance of our mutual contractual obligations and/or carried out with your consent.  
To communicate with you to verify your account and for informational and operational purposes (e.g., account management, customer service, system maintenance), including by periodically emailing you Services-related announcements.| This processing is necessary for the performance of our mutual contractual obligations and/or carried out with your consent.  
To give you access to our support and customer care Services and to enable you to communicate with our team.| This processing is necessary for the performance of our mutual contractual obligations, carried out with your consent and/or necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.  
To ensure compliance with any applicable laws, our Services’ terms and conditions, and our Privacy Policy.| This processing is necessary for the performance of our mutual contractual obligations and/or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.  
To send information to authorized third-parties (e.g., customers, end-users, etc.).| This processing is necessary for the performance of our mutual contractual obligations and/or carried out with your consent  
To send marketing materials, as well as suggestions and recommendations on our services that may be of interest to you.| This processing is based on your consent.  
To carry on statistical research / analysis of aggregated or anonymous data, without identifying you, as well as to measure and evaluate the operation of our Site, its traffic and usability.| This processing does not involve the processing of Personal Data.  
To the fulfill a legal obligation to which we are subject or to ascertain, exercise or defend a right in Court or whenever an authority exercises its jurisdiction.| This processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.  
  
 **2.2. Voluntary nature of the processing.** Providing your Personal Data for the above-mentioned purposes is voluntary and not mandatory. However, any refusal to provide any of such data may not allow us to establish and/or continue a contractual relationship with you, or to fulfill your requests, or to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject.

#### SECT. 3 - WHAT IS DATA RETENTION PERIOD AND WHAT SECURITY MEASURES HAVE BEEN TAKEN FOR YOUR PERSONAL DATA SAFEGUARD

 **3.1. Data retention.** Personal Data collected by us will be processed for the time strictly necessary to achieve the purposes referred to in above. In particular:

 **3.1.a.** Personal Data collected through the provision of Services or Newsletter will be deleted (or anonymized for statistical purposes) only after you unsubscribe.

 **3.1.b.** Personal Data needed for the provision of our newsletter service will be processed until you decide to unsubscribe;

 **3.1.c.** Personal Data whose retention is mandatory under the applicable laws (e.g., tax laws, bookkeeping, etc.) will be retained for a period of time necessary or permitted to comply with such laws.

 **3.2. Security measures.** We warrant to maintains and continue to maintain appropriate and sufficient technical and organizational security measures to protect your Personal Data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, damage, alteration, unauthorized disclosure or access, in particular where the Processing involves the transmission of data over a network, and against all other unlawful forms of processing. Please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. So, while we strive to protect your data, we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss or a data breach will never occur. Notwithstanding the preceding, we operate with the aim of mitigating the risks associated with processing your Personal Data through several measures, including :

 **3.2.a. Data Minimization.** We only ever obtain, retain, process and share Personal Data that is essential to carry out our services and legal obligations: only that which is relevant and necessary is collected. In particular, by way of example, our electronic collections (i.e., via the Site, etc.), have only fields that are relevant to the purpose of collection and subsequent processing, while the physical collection (i.e., face-to-face contacts, phone calls, etc.) is supported using scripts and internal forms using predefined fields.

 **3.2.b. Pseudonymization.** Whenever possible, we utilize pseudonymization to record and store Personal Data in a way that ensures that such data can no longer be attributed to a specific data subject without the use of separate additional information (i.e., personal identifiers) which are protected with encryption, partitioning and other technical and operational measures of risk reduction and data protection.

 **3.2.c. Encryption.** Although we use encryption (i.e., using a secret key to make Personal Data indecipherable unless decryption of the dataset is carried out using such assigned key) as a form of pseudonymization, we also utilize it as a secondary risk prevention measure for securing the Personal Data that we process. In particular, we utilize SSL (Secure Socket Layer) protocols for transferring Personal Data to any external party (such as, our payment processor).

 **3.2.d. PCI Compliance.** We are compliant with Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), in order to protect your Personal Data against fraud and payment card theft.

 **3.2.e. Access restriction.** We use company-wide restriction methods for restricting access into the foundation of our processes, systems and structure, in order to ensure that only those with authorization and/or a relevant purpose, have access to Personal Data. Special category data is restricted at all levels and can only be accessed by our authorized personnel.

 **3.2.f. No hard copy data.** We never store any Personal Data in hard copy format.

#### SECT. 4 - WHO ARE THE RECIPIENTS OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA

4.1. Third-party service providers or consultants. We engage certain trusted third parties to perform functions and provide services to us, including hosting and maintenance, error monitoring, debugging, performance monitoring, billing, customer relationship, database storage and management, and direct marketing campaigns. We may share your Personal Information with these third parties, but only to the extent necessary to perform these functions and provide such services. We also require these third parties to maintain the privacy and security of your Personal Data they process on our behalf. In particular, without limiting the foregoing, our principal third-party service providers are our mail marketing service provider (i.e., Mailchimp, see https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and our online payment service provider (i.e., Bluesnap, see https://home.bluesnap.com/privacy-policy/), to which your financial data are communicated at the purpose to invoice our Services that you purchased.

 **4.2. Other Third Parties.** We may share Personal Data with our headquarters and affiliates, and business partners to whom it is reasonably necessary or desirable for us to disclose your data for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

 **4.3. Third parties required by laws or authorities.** We may disclose your data to a third party if (i) we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request (including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements), (ii) to enforce our agreements and policies, (iii) to protect the security or integrity of our services and products, (iv) to protect ourselves, our other customers, or the public from harm or illegal activities, or (v) to respond to an emergency which we believe in good faith requires us to disclose data to assist in preventing a death or serious bodily injury. If we are required by law to disclose any of your Personal Data, then we will use reasonable efforts to provide you with notice of that disclosure requirement, unless we are prohibited from doing so by statute, subpoena or court or administrative order. Further, we object to requests that we do not believe were issued properly.

 **4.4. Aggregated or de-identified data.** We may also make certain non-Personal Data (i.e., data which has been de-identified or aggregated in a way that does not directly identify you) available to third parties for various purposes, including for business or marketing purposes or to assist third parties in understanding our users’ interest, habits, and usage patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and functionality available through the Services.

#### SECT. 5 - WHERE YOUR PERSONAL DATA MAY BE TRANSFERRED

We are based in India, but your Personal Data may be transferred to, and stored at, any of our affiliates, partners or service providers mentioned in previous Sect. 4, which may be either inside or outside the European Economic Area. Your Personal Data may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information, but we ensure that when we transfer or disclose your Personal Data to such other countries, we will protect that information as described in this Privacy Policy. By submitting your Personal Data, you agree to such transfers.

#### SECT. 6 - YOUR RIGHTS

 **6.1. Right of access.** You are always entitled to receive confirmation as to whether or not your Personal Data are being processed and, where that is the case, access and receive copy of such Personal Data in an intelligible form. Furthermore, you are also entitled to receive information concerning: the purposes of the processing; the categories of Personal Data concerned; the recipients (or categories thereof) to whom the Personal Data have been or will be disclosed; where possible, the envisaged period for which the Personal Data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period; the existence of the right to request from us rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing of your Personal Data or to object to such processing; the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority; the source of the Personal Data; the existence of automated decision-making; where Personal Data are transferred to a third country or to an international organization, the appropriate safeguards relating to the transfer.

 **6.2. Right to withdraw consent.** You are always entitled to withdraw, at any time, your consent to the processing of your Personal Data, both on legitimate grounds (even though they are relevant to the purpose of the collection) and if the processing is carried out for direct marketing purpose. The preceding will not affect the lawfulness of processing based on consent before the withdrawal.

 **6.3. Right to rectification, erasure and restriction.** You are always entitled to obtain from us, without undue delay: the rectification or integration of your Personal Data that are inaccurate or incomplete; the erasure of your Personal Data that have been processed unlawfully or whose retention is unnecessary for the Purposes; the restriction of processing, in case you challenge either the accuracy of your Personal data or the lawfulness of the processing, or in case we no longer need the Personal Data for the Purposes, but they are required by you for the establishment, exercise or defense of a legal claim.

 **6.4. Right to data portability.** You have the right to receive your Personal Data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, as well as the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from us, where technically feasible.

 **6.5. Right to lodge a complaint before an European supervisory authority.** In case you are an European citizen, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Supervisory Authority located in your place of residence.

 **6.6. Contacts.** Requests to exercise the rights above must be sent to ****IT 2002, IT ZONE, RAMCHANDRAPURA INDUS. AREA, SITAPURA, JAIPUR, Rajasthan (India)**** , or by e-mail to [care@sketchbubble.com](mailto:care@sketchbubble.com). Any access request is always completed within one month; however, where the retrieval or provision of information is particularly complex or is subject to a valid delay, the period may be extended by two further months. If this is the case, we will write to the individual within one month and keep him/her informed of the delay and the reasons thereof.

#### SECT. 7 - AMENDMENTS TO THIS POLICY

This Privacy Policy came into force on the date specified above. We reserve the right to amend or to update its content, whether in whole or in part, also following changes in the legal and regulatory obligations regarding data protection. We will inform you on such amendments and updates through their publication on the Site as soon as they are adopted, and they will be binding from the moment of their publication . Therefore, we invite you to visit this section of the Site regularly, in order to be aware of the most recent and updated version thereof, so that you are always updated on the processing activities that we carry out.
